Guide to the ILGWU Records, 1884-2006, bulk 1923-1995.
ILGWU Records, 1884-2006, bulk 1923-1995.
- SERIES VII. DEPARTMENTS AND INSTITUTIONS, 1884-1999
  - 5780/196. Operations Department. Industrial Homework records, 1986-1989., Contains reports, comments, testimonies, and statements submitted by the ILGWU and other interested organizations and individuals concerning revisions to the federal regulation of employment of homeworkers in certain industries, proposed between 1986 and 1989.
  - 5780/202. Operations Department. Collective Bargaining Agrements, [1988-1995.], This collection includes records from both the Research Department and the Operations Department. Arranged alphabetically by company, these records consist of collective bargaining agreements negotiated by local unions of the ILGWU and various companies.
  - 5780/202 PUBS. Operations Department. Operations standards manuals, 1983-1984., Consists of operations standards manuals for women’s blouses for 1983 and 1984, and women’s skirts for 1984.
  - 5780/144. Organizing Department records, 1979-1989., Arranged alphabetically, these records include correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed material created or collected by the Organizing Department, and other material relating to its activities between 1961 and 1989. In addition to documeint routine operations of the department, these records also include documentation of efforts to roll back imports, including reports on congressional visits on a resolution on the subject. Also included are monthly reports on organizing activities from joint boards and regional departments, as well as periodic reports submitted by local unions’, joint boards’, and regional departments’ organizing departments to the central organizing department; these reports include names of organizers and shops organized, and descriptions of current, future, and abandoned campaigns that were to be included in the Organizing Department’s reports to the General Executive Board.
  - 5780/205. Company files. [1971-1995.], Contains Dun and Bradstreet Report on companies, reports on the companies’ activities with non-ILGWU firms, memoranda on companies and efforts to organize workers therein, as well as some authorization cards.
  - 5780/151. Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE) records, 1976-1990., Contains chronological correspondence files and financial records of the Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE) of the ILGWU. Also included in this collection files relating to hearings before the National Labor Relations Board regarding the organization of workers of the Central Tax Bureau of Pennsylvania and the Burlington News Agency (Burlington, Vermont); these files include correspondence, transcripts of hearings, notes on visits to workers, and organizers' weekly reports.
  - 5780/119. Political Department. Evelyn Dubrow papers, [1964-1978.], This collection contains Evelyn Dubrow’s correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to the her lobbying activities in Washington, D.C. Also contained in this collection are letters and receipts documenting campaign contributions, alphabetical files on states, as well as files on local unions, joint boards, and regional departments. The records of the Political Department also contain ephemeral printed material relating to political campaigns, including pamphlets, posters, and fliers.
  - 5780/103. Political Department records, 1962-1983., This collection contains correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to the Political Department’s lobbying activities in Washington, D.C. Also contained in this collection are letters and receipts documenting campaign contributions, alphabetical files on states, as well as files on local unions, joint boards, and regional departments. The records of the Political Department also contain ephemeral printed material relating to political campaigns, including pamphlets, posters, and fliers.
  - 5780/142. Political and Legislative Department. Evelyn Dubrow papers, 1985-1995., This collection contains Evelyn Dubrow’s correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to her lobbying activities in Washington, D.C. Also contained in this collection are letters and receipts documenting campaign contributions, alphabetical files on states, as well as files on local unions, joint boards, and regional departments. The records of the Political Department also contain ephemeral printed material relating to political campaigns, including pamphlets, posters, and fliers.
  - 5780/105. Research Department records, [1921-1983.], This collection contains the papers of Lazare Teper. In addition to subject files and correspondence, Teper’s papers include files relating to the Wage Stabilization Board, including correspondence regarding applications to the board, compensation adjustment, approval of fringe benefits, and proposed health and welfare plans.
  - 5780/045. Research Department records, 1884-1948., Contains records of predecessor unions and locals of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, including the United Brotherhood of Cloakmakers, Local 1; Knights of Labor, Sanctuary Local Assembly 3038; Unity House Committee of Locals 22, 25, 60, and 66; United Progessive League of Cloak and Dressmakers; United Progressive League of Local 1; Skirtmakers' Union, Local 5; ILGWU Research Department; Cincinnati Joint Board; Local 60, and Local 63.
  - 5780/123. Research Department records, [1907-1980.], This collection contains records of the National Coat and Suit Industry Board (statements of receipts and disbursements, label division reports, meetings minutes, bulletins to members, and other reports and resolutions), as well as some legal files.
  - 5780/056. Research Department records, 1907-1948, 1910-1940 (bulk)., Financial and administrative reports, meeting minutes, correspondence, and other materials documenting the activities and interests of the ILGWU Research Department. Much of the material concerns various strikes, including the New York cloakmakers' strikes of 1926 and 1929, as well as the "Protocol of Peace" of 1910. There are some additional items dealing with the New York Cloak Joint Board. A good portion of the material is administrative in nature.
  - 5780/168. Research Department records, 1890-1971., These files contain books, journals, reports, pamphlets, advertisements, and correspondence of the Research Department of the International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union. Also included are correspondence of Lazare Teper, organizational material from local unions all over the United States, reports and writings by Research Department staff (including analyses of strikes between 1940 and 1945), files on the Cone Mills and S. Lichtenberg campaigns, as well as documents collected by the department. Among the documents collected by the Research Department are the New York Coat and Suit Industry Reports between 1934 and 1960.
  - 5780/209. Research Department records, [1945-1995.], Series I contains statements on issues related to the garment industry filed by the ILGWU between 1965 and 1995. Series II contains correspondence with non-ILGWU organizations and individuals, arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject. Series III contains correspondence with ILGWU officers and staff, including staff of local unions, joint boards and councils, and regional departments and offices; Series IV contains files on miscellaneous subjects. Series V consists of the Research Department’s outgoing letters between 1964 and 1991.
  - 5780/078. Research Department reports, 1938-1985., This collection contains reports from the Research Department, including its annual “Conditions in the Women’s Clothing Industry.”
  - 5780/163. Research Department. US National Industry Recovery Administration (NIRA) Hearings files, 1933-1937., This collection contains reports and records of hearings held by the United States National Industrial Recovery Administration between 1933 and 1937. Topics of these hearings include Code of Fair Practices and Competition, Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee Employment, Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, as well as hearings on amendments, history and violations of code.
  - 5780/148. Research Department wages and hours files, 1938-1942, 1950-1975., This collection contains extensive files of hearings before, proceedings of, and memoranda and briefs submitted to the Department of Labor’s Wage and Hours Division between 1938 and 1942, and 1950 and 1975. Committees represented in these files include: Apparel Industry Committee, Button and Buckle Manufacturing Industry Committee, Embroideries Committee, Hosiery Industry Committee, Knitted and Men’s Woven Underwear and Commercial Knitting Industry Committee, Knitted Outerwear Committee, Knitted Underwear and Commercial Knitting Industry Committee, Miscellaneous Apparel Industry Committee, Special Industry Committee for Puerto Rico, Textile Industry Committee, and the Women’s Apparel Industry Committee. Also included in this collection are records of the Department of Labor’s Public Contract Division and Research and Statistics Division.
  - 5780/175. Termination analysis log books, 1979-1980., Personnel profiles on employees who were suspended or terminated, as well as the reason for the action. Personnel information includes gender, marital status, race, and wages of employees suspended or terminated at particular firms.
  - 5780/099. Retiree Service Department. David Dubinsky papers, 1968-1982., This collection contains correspondence, memoranda, vouchers, and other material that document the work of the Department of Retiree Services, including requests submitted to the department for funds in support of retiree groups and related activities, and notification of decisions of whether to fund these requests and award amount. Also included in this subseries are collected printed material and drafts of department publications.
  - 5780/184. Training Institute. Evaluation Forms, ca. 1951-1965., This is a restricted collection consisting of evaluations of trainees from the years 1952, 1959, and 1965.
  - 5780/060. Union Health Center records, 1911-1977, 1920-1960 (bulk)., Correspondence, annual reports, articles, financial statements, and other materials documenting the evolving role of the ILGWU Union Health Center. Much of the material is routine or administrative in nature. Other items in the collection include articles by such figures as George M. Price and Pauline Newman, the Center's director, on the issue of union health centers generally and the ILGWU Center in particular.
  - 5780/171. Union Health Center. Publications, 1912-1986., This collection contains booklets and pamphlets by and about the Union Health Center, as well as some reports of the Joint Board of Sanitary Control.
  - 5780/122. Unity House records, 1971-1993., This collection includes files on the renovation of Unity House. Also included is a 1993 article on the history of the ILGWU in Northern Pennsylvania.
  - 5780/122 MB. Unity House memorabilia., This collection contains memorabilia, including printed material from Unity House (pamphlets, brochures, and placemats), approval for a liquor license from the Pennsylvania Liquor Control Board, and portraits of David Dubinsky and Sol Chaikin.
- SERIES VIII. PRINTED MATERIAL, 1910-1995
  - Official Organs of the ILGWU, 1910-1995
    - 5780/070. Ladies' Garment Worker, 1911-1917., Collection consists of issues of the Ladies’ Garment Worker published between 1911 and 1917. Issues from the publication’s first year (1910) and its final year (1918) are available on microfilm.
    - 5780/051 mf. Justice. Microfilm, 1919-1976., Contains issues of Justice published between 1919 and 1976.
    - 5780/051 PUBS. Justice, 1975-1995., Contains issues of Justice published between 1975 and 1995.
    - 5780/180. Justice. Index, 1947-1979., This collection consists of yearly indexes to Justice, the official organ of the International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union.
    - 5780/185 mf. Gerechtigkeit (Justice), 1919-1957. Microfilm., This collection contains issues of Gerchtigheit, the Yiddish-language edition of the ILGWU’s official organ Justice.
    - 5780/186. Giustizia (Justice), 1950-1970. Microfilm., This collection contains issues of Giustizia, the Italian-language edition of the ILGWU’s official organ Justice
    - 5780/186 mf. Giustizia (Justice), 1919-1946. Microfilm., This collection contains issues of Giustizia, the Italian-language edition of the ILGWU’s official organ Justice.
    - 5780/201. Justicia, This collection contains issues of Justicia, the Spanish-language edition of the ILGWU’s official organ Justice.
  - Other printed material, 1910-1995
    - 5780 PUBS. Publications.
    - 5780/124. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Current Bulletin and Weekly Market Letter, 1939-1953., This collection contains Current Bulletin, Weekly Market Letter, and Style and Merchandise Review, publications of the Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Manufacturers.
    - 5780/169. Local Publications, 1914-1975., This collection contains publications of several locals, joint boards, and departments of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. In addition to periodicals, this collection contains pamphlets, reports, anniversary programs, and other publications from local unions.
    - 5780/172. Canadian Publications, 1936-1984., This collection includes Canadian publications by and about the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
    - 5780/125. Newspapers, [1913-1980.], This collection consists of publications either produced or collected by the ILGWU. It includes periodicals of local unions, joint boards, and the international periodicals, as well as publications from other organizations.
    - 5780/159. Abraham Rosenberg. Memoirs of a Cloak Maker. Papers and microfilm, 1883-1910., This collection contains a bound volume of photocopies of a cloakmaker's memoirs. The memoirs were translated by Yetta Horn.
    - 5780/167. Unpublished union histories, 1911-1971., Manuscripts, typescripts, and bound volumes containing unpublished histories of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Authors include Julius Hochman, Abraham Rosenberg, and Fannia Cohn.
    - 5780/178. Charles Zimmerman, collector. Radical pamphlets, 1914-1958., This collection consist of pamphlets and other printed material collected by Charles Zimmerman.
- SERIES IX. AUDIO-VISUAL, 1885-1995
  - 5780 AV. Audiovisual collection., This collection contains video recordings, audio recordings, motion picture film, microfilm, and film strips collected, produced or otherwise created by the ILGWU. Available on DVD are films and videos of ILGWU conventions, the ILGWU Management-Engineering Department’s time and motion studies, Union Label commercials, the 50th anniversary of the Union Health Center. Other recordings document local union activities, lectures at the ILGWU’s Training Institute, speeches by union leaders, interviews with union officials on radio and television programs. This collection also contains microfilmed records of the Auditing Department and the Finance Department.
  - 5780 F. Films., This collection contains films collected, produced or otherwise created by the ILGWU. The ILGWU circulated films from its international headquarters to local unions, schools, and other organizations. Included are films documenting rallies, international conventions, local union meetings, and recreational outings.
  - 5780 OH. Oral histories, 1973-1986., This collection contains recordings of oral history interviews with officers, staff, and members of the ILGWU.
  - 5780 P. Photographs., This collection contains photographs and photographic negatives documenting the work of the ILGWU. Included are photographs used in the production of ILGWU publications (including but not limited to the union’s official organ, Justice); snapshots from local, national, and international activities; photographs mounted for display in the ILGWU Archives, local union and international offices; portraits of officers; group photographs of local members, delegates, and committees; and photographs of union buildings and offices.
  - 5780 Perm. Permanent exhibit., Consists of items that were part of the ILGWU's permanent exhibit in New York City on the history of the union.
  - 5780/098. Paintings and memorabilia, 1952-1979., Paintings, drawings, plaques, certificates, proclamations, scrapbooks, and sketches generated by the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
  - 5780/102 P. Justice. Photographs, 1910-1990., This collection contains photographs used in, or considered for use in, Justice. Photographs document a wide range of ILGWU activities and institutions, as well as many ILGWU members, staff, and officers.
  - 5780/109. Broadsides, 1907-1980., This collection consists of broadsides created or collected by the International Ladies Garment Workers Union.
  - 5780/110 OHT. Oral history transcripts, 1966-1986., This collection consists of transcripts of oral history interviews with 45 officers, staff, and members of the ILGWU.
  - 5780/112. Exhibit display panels., This collection consists of garment workers posters, featuring motifs of women and children.
  - 5780/125 G. Photographs and ad boards, This collection consists of fliers, posters, and broadsides produced and distributed by the ILGWU. Some of these materials announce meetings, rallies, and other events; others more generally relate to the garment industry.
  - 5780/134 AV. Miscellaneous audio cassettes, 1948-1985., This collection consists of audio cassettes covering a range of events and topics. Included are lectures by ILGWU staff, speeches by Sol Chaikin, media coverage of David Dubinsky's death, conventions, conferences, and other union functions, as well as interviews with cast members from the ILGWU musical production "Pins and Needles."
- SERIES X. SCRAPBOOKS AND MEMORABILIA
  - 5780 MB. Memorabilia., This collection consists of various collectibles from the ILGWU, such as badges, buttons, ball-point pens, tie tacks, money clips, newspaper articles, plaques, photos, scarf, t-shirt, books and more.
  - 5780/127. America's Next Great Designer Competition. Scrapbooks, 1968, 1975-1982., Collection contains scrapbooks concerning the America's Next Great Designer Award, an annual award established in 1976 and sponsored by the ILGWU.
  - 5780/128. Women's Wear Daily scrapbooks, 1977-1985., This collection consists of scrapbooks containing clippings from Women’s Wear Daily from 1977 to 1985. While some articles feature the ILGWU, others address the women’s garment industry more generally.
  - 5780/160. Scrapbooks, 1910-1958., This collection contains scrapbooks assembled by officers and members of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. The scrapbooks primarily contain news clippings.
  - 5780/160mf. American Labor Party news article scrapbook, 1937-1941., This collection consists of a scrapbook of newsclippings about the American Labor Party.
  - 5780/170. People v. Benedict Macri. Legal transcripts and scrapbook, 1949-1957., Collection consists of materials pertaining to the 1949 murder of William Lurye, an organizer for the ILGWU, and the 1951 trial of Benedict Macri, who was acquitted of the crime. Documents include a scrapbook of news clippings on the case, a wanted poster for the fugitive suspect John Giusto, and the court transcript of Macri's trial.
  - 5780/173. Gold Bond Certificates, 1928-1932., This collection consists of samples of Gold Bond certificates of different denominations, as well as related notes, correspondence, receipts, and contribution lists.
  - 5780/181m. Memorabilia. WFDR-FM Inaugural Broadcast Program, 1949, WFDR-FM was a non-profit radio station in New York City, owned and operated by the ILGWU from 1949 to 1952. This collection consists of one program issued on the occasion of WFDR-FM’s inaugural broadcast.
  - 5780/188 MB. Banners., Contains banners created or used by the ILGWU at union events.
  - 5780/197 MB. Kitty Goldstein memorabilia, 1891-1950., This collection consists of photographs, Constitution and Receipt book for ILGWU, Local 23, and Kattie Goldstein's birth certificate (born Chelio Leea Golstain (Chaya Leah Goldstein)). Items are brittle.
- SERIES XI. MISCELLANY
  - 5780/061. Miscellany, 1895-1992., This collection consists of letters, printed material, and case files from various departments and individuals within the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Included are files of John A. Dyche, Harry Greenberg, Herman Grossman, Louis Hyman, Charles Jacobson, Edward Kramer, Charles Kreindler, Charles Baker, Rose Pesotta, and Harry Uviller.
  - 5780/200. Miscellany, [1904-1986.], This collection contains assorted periodicals, including issues of Justice, Giustizia, and Die Gleichheit.